Finding Aid for the Grantland Rice Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Newspaper clippings of poems, articles, and columns by Grantland Rice
  - Index of all poems, articles, and columns by Grantland Rice
    - The Why and the Wherefore (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Why Gans and Nelson Will Fight on Level (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Why Is It-- (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Why Not? (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Why They Gall It 'Horse Sense'
    - Wild Animals I Have Known (Box 4, Folder 16, Box 5, Folder 3)
    - William Randolph Hearst (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Will-o'-the-Wisps (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Wind of the Night (Box 4, Folder 25, Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Wind of the North (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Wind of the South (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Winds in the Palms (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Winds of Sport (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Winds of the World (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Winds of Yesterday (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - The Winning Month (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - The Winning Road (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - The Winning System (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - The Winning Tip (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Winter in New York (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Winter in the U.S.A. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Winter Indeed (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 'Winter League Carol (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - The Winter League Opens (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - The Winter League Wonder (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - A Winter Reverie (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - The Winter Road (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Winter Sport (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Winter Tip to Hoss Players (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Winter's Coming Relief (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - A Wintry Confession (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Wise and Near-Wise (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - The Wise Cove Speaks (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Wise George (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Wise Moth (Box 4, Folder 27, Box 6, Folder 29)
    - A Wish (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - With Apologies 5-151 31 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - With Rag and Pick (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - The Woodland, the Fields, and the Lane (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - The World of the Human (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - The World Topsy-Turvy (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Wouldn't You? (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Wraith of the Years (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Wraiths (Box 4, Folder 18, 19)
    - The Wreck (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Writing to Santa (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Yale Asks a Question (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - The Yale of Other Days (Box 5, Folder 11, Box 6, Folder 30)
    - A Yarn of the Off-Season (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - The Year Is Going? Let 'er Go. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - A Yearning (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Yes, Go Away (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Yes It Is (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Yes, It Might Be Worse (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Yesterdays and Tomorrows (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - You Are Old, Father Dodger (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - You're Pitching to the Wrong Home Plate (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - You've Had It Happen (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - You Know Him (Box 5, Folder 15, Box 7, Folder 7)
    - You Know It (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - You Said It (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Your Winter's Choice (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - The Youth Maker (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Young April (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Young Spring (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Zero Weather--An Antidote (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - The Zoo Is Loose (Box 7, Folder 47, Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous verse from scrapbooks: pages from a series of scrapbooks of Grantland Rice's poems, clipped from newspapers like Cleveland News, Nashville Tennessean, New York Mail, etc., circa before 1914 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous verse from scrapbooks: pages from a series of scrapbooks of Grantland Rice's poems, clipped from newspapers like Cleveland News, Nashville Tennessean, New York Mail, etc., circa before 1914 (Box 5, Folder 1-15)
  - Early columns (Tennessee'uns, Sportograms, etc.), undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "We Have With Us Today" (with J.N. Ding), March 21-May 30, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
  - Individual poems (i.e., not from columns) (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
  - Individual poems (i.e., not from columns), undated (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
  - Reprinted poems (Box 5, Folder 23-24)
  - Verse from columns, undated (Box 5, Folder 25-29)
  - Prose writings (Box 5, Folder 30-36)
    Miscellaneous prose includes "In the Training Camp" (1919), Irvin S. Cobb obituary etc.; The Tumult and the Shouting serial from the Boston Daily Globe, Jan. 2-22, 1955.
  - "The Sportlight" (Box 6, Box 7, Folder 1-47)
    - The Sportlight: Then and Now (1935-1936) (Winter Sports Series), illustrated columns
      This series contains a list of illustrated columns. Corresponding photographs for the columns can be found in boxes 13 and 14.
      - Bobby Jones and Lawson Little (a Little, b Jones), Dec. 16, 1935 (Box 7)
      - Dean, Johnson and Matty (a Dizzy Dean, b Walter Johnson, c Christy Mathewson), Dec. 19, 1935 (Box 7)
      - Tilden and Perry (a Fred Perry, b Bill Tilden), Dec. 23, 1935 (Box 7)
      - Louis, 1935; Dempsey, 1919 (a Joe Louis w/ Max Baer; b Jack Dempsey w/ Jess Willard), Dec. 26, 1935 (Box 7)
      - Cobb and Vaughan (a Ty Cobb, b Arky Vaughan), Dec. 30, 1935 (Box 7)
      - Man o' War and Discovery (a Man o' War, b Discovery), Jan. 2, 1936 (Box 7)
      - Thorpe and Berwanger (a Jim Thorpe, b Jay Berwanger), Jan. 6, 1936 (Box 7)
      - Ruth, Gehrig, and Foxx (a Babe Ruth, b Lou Gehrig, c Jimmy Foxx), Jan. 9, 1936 (Box 7)
      - Harry Vardon and Walter Hagen (a Vardon, b Hagen), Jan. 13, 1936 (Box 7)
      - Joyce and Glenna (a Joyce Wethered, b Glenna Collett Vare), Jan. 16, 1936 (Box 7)
      - Lenglen and Moody (a Suzanne Lenglen, b Helen Wills Moody), Jan. 20, 1936 (Box 7)
  - "The Sport Parade", This series contains a list of illustrated columns. Corresponding photographs for the columns can be found in boxes 13 and 14. (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
    - "The Sport Parade", illustrated columns, This series contains a list of illustrated columns. Corresponding photographs for the columns can be found in boxes 13 and 14. (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Mailed Fist of Mauraee Bay (Dempsey--Willard), Feb. 5, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Master Mandarin's Final Magic (Knute Rockne), Feb. 6, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Perfect Human Machine Arrives (Billy Carr), Feb. 7, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When Orioles Were Eagles (Willie Keeler, Hughey Jennings, Joe Kelley, John J. McGraw, Tommy Murphy), Feb. 9, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Old Master Bows to Time and Disease (Joe Gans), Feb. 10, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Hell Pops in Helensville (Helen Jacobs), Feb. 12, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Head, Heart and Arm--That Was Bix Six in His Prime (Christy Mathewson), Feb. 13, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Kid Who Put Golf on the Sporting Page (Francis Ouimet), Feb. 14, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Speed Demons of 1906 (Alfred G. Vanderbilt and Mrs. Oliver Iselin), Feb. 15, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Iron Fist Falls on the Orchid (Jack Dempsey--Georges Carpentieri, Feb. 16, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Man Who Laughed at Death (Barney üldfield), Feb. 17, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Flying Dutchman in His Day of Glory (John J. McGraw), Feb. 19, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Golfing Princess Who Became a Queen (Glenna Collett Vare), Feb. 20, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Track on Fire--Spinning the Mile in 4.07.4 (Jack Lovelock--Bill Bo thron), Feb. 23, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Long Count (Dempsey--Tunney), Feb. 26, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Texas Tornado--Female Ruler of All the Babe's (Babe Didrikson), Feb. 28, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Two Old Masters in One Frame (Harry Vardon--Walter J. Travis), Mar. 1, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When Big Babe Was the Game's Best Pitcher (Babe Ruth), Mar. 2, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Queen Abdicates (Suzanne Lenglen), Mar. 3, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The First Big Four of Polo and the Battalion of Death (Harry Payne Whitney, Devereux Milburn, Monty Waterbury, Larry Waterbury; Major Barrett, Captain Cheape, Captain Tompkinson, Captain Lockett), Mar. 5, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Frank Chance, the Peerless Leader, Gets a Cub Score, Mar. 6, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Paths of Hate that Crossed Again (James J. Corbett, John L. Sullivan), (Mar. 7, 19 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Galloping Ghost with the Snaky Hips (Red Grange), Mar. 8, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Comet that Flamed--and Made a Game (Maurice McLoughlin), Mar. 9, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A $2,000,000 Crown Crashes through the Ropes (Dempsey--Luis Angel Firpo), Mar. 10, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Golfing Smiths--The Game's Greatest Family (Willie, Alex, Mama, George, Papa, Jim, and McDonald Smith), Mar. 13, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Master Showman with His Cane and Gold (Tex Rickard, Jack Gleason, Jack Johnson), Mar. 14, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Picture of Prophecy--The Salute before Eternal Sleep (Anthony F. Wilding), Mar. 15, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When Haughton Made Harvard Forget the Lowells and the Cabots (Percy Haughton), Mar. 16, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Great Haig--20 Years Ago (Walter Hagen), Mar. 17, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - What a Challenger for Max Baer in Any Night Club! (Jem Mace), Mar. 20, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - For the Mastery of the Seas (Shamrock IV and Resolute), Mar. 21, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - His Quick Wit and Gay Spirit Still Live On (Tiny Maxwell), Mar. 22, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Most Famous Pigtails Known to Sport (Helen Wills w/ Winifred Suer), Mar. 24, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Just before a Champion Falls (Jack Johnson, Tommy Burns), Mar. 26, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Great Australian (Norman Brookes), Mar. 29, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Paoli Phenom--Record Holder (Cy Young), Mar. 31, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Two Chins Crack as One in Double K.O. (Ad Wolgast, Joe Rivers), Apr. 2, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Great Run--to the Wrong Goal (Roy Reigels), Apr. 3, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - First Act of a Thrilling Drama--The Great Default (Suzanne Lenglen, Molla Mallory), Apr. 4, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Georgia Ghost Shows His Dust (Ty Cobb), Apr. 5, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The First President to Sink a Putt or Slice a Drive (William Howard Taft), Apr. 6, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When Marvelous Molla Was Miss Bjurstedt (Molla Mallory), Apr. 9, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Sportsman to the Final Breath (Harry Payne Whitney, Louis Stoddard), Apr. 10, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - This Has Happened Over 700 Times (Babe Ruth), Apr. 11, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Silent Man from Tennessee (Edward "Pop" Geers), Apr. 12, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The First Open Golf Chamption--And the Game's Big Change (Horace Rawlings), Apr. 13, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - King of the Second Sackers (Eddie Collins), Apr. 16, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When Big Bill Was Just Another Tennis Player (Bill Tilden), Apr. 17, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Disembodied Ghost (Frank Hinkey), Apr. 18, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The First "Fastest Human" (Arthur Duffy), Apr. 19, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Kid Phenom Who Is Still a Star at Fifty (H. Chandler Egan), Apr. 20, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Terrible Terry Comes to Journey's End (Terry McGovern), Apr. 21, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Great Gipp (George Gipp), Dec. 11, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Two Baseball Immortals (Hank Gowdy, Rabbit Maranville), Dec. 13, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The First of the Fastest Humans (Arthur Duffy), Dec. 14, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Twenty Years Later--After 19 Straight (Rube Marquard), Dec. 15, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Height of Form and Fashion, 30 Years Ago (ladies golfing, 1900), Dec. 17, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Baseball's Greatest Iron Man (Lou Gehrig), Dec. 18, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - "Count over Him--He'll Get Up" (Stanley Ketchell), Dec. 21, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When Terrible Terry Failed Again (Corbett-McGovern), Dec. 22, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The King of Sporting Veterans (George Wright), Dec. 24, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Triple Winner--And a Double Star (Mary K. Browne), Dec. 25, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Pictorial Career of John Joseph McGraw, Nos. 1-4 (J. J. McGraw), Dec. 26, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When the Orioles Were Early Birds 40 Years Ago (McGraw, Keeler, Gleason, Kelley, Hanlon, Robinson, Hoffer, and Jennings), Dec. 31, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Ruby Robert's Victory Smile (Bob Fitzsimmons--Jim Corbett), Jan. 1, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Wizard at the Age of 12 (Willie Hoppe), Jan. 2, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The First of the Greater Milers (John Paul Jones), Jan. 3, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Human Splinter (Johnny Evers), Jan. 4, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The ball Player Who Slipped Science into Hitting (Willie Keeler), Jan. 5, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Killed in Action--R.I.P. (Johnny Overton), Jan. 7, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When the "EE-Yah" Battle Cry Rang Out (Hughey Jennings), Jan. 8, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Delivery that Lives in Memory (Christy Mathewson), Jan. 10, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Her Name Coined a Sporting Classic (Annie Oakley), Dec. 19, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Kid that Used to Be (Norman Selby "Kid McCoy), Jan. 11, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Journey's End for the Old Master (Joe Gans), Jan. 15, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Veteran Who Laughs Away the Years (Connie Mack, Thomas S. Shibe), Jan. 17, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Title that Bounded from a Rock (Harold Hilton), Jan. 18, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Star that Stopped a Comet (Richard Norris Williams), Jan. 19, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The World of Sport Also Moves Along (Harriet Curtis, Beatrice Gottlieb), Jan. 21, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When the Big Wheel Was the Top of Sport (bicycling, 1895), Jan. 22, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When Jeffries and Tom Sharkey Met (Jim Jeffries, Tom Sharkey, Jan. 23, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Forty Years and No Off-Day (Keene Fitzpatrick), Jan. 24, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Shoeless Joe Jackson--Master Hitter (Joe Jackson), Jan. 25, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The All-Time Quarterback (Walter Eckersall), Jan. 26, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Famous Feud of Fistiana (John L. Sullivan--Peter Jackson), Jan. 28, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Star Teacher--And Three Star Pupils (Stewart Maiden; Alexa Stirling, Bobby Jones, Perry Adair), Jan. 29, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When Sport Also Started a War (Dorando, London Olympics, 1908), Jan. 30, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Fame of the Rabbit Still Lives (Rabbit Maranville), Jan. 31, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Far Away and Long Ago (tennis, 1880's), Feb. 1, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When Queens of Golf Fought for a Kingdom (Glenna Collett, Joyce Wethered), Feb. 2, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The World's Longest Golf Match (Billy Burke, George Von Elm), Feb. 4, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The King of Tennis Competitors (Bill Johnston, Bill Tilden), Feb. 5, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Max Baer--From the Cradle to the Crown (Baer with sister, Fanny; Baer-- Tommy Loughran; Baer--Max Schmeling; Baer--Camera), Feb.6-9, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When a Golf Queen Was a Princess (Virginia Van Wie), Feb. 11, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Few Sidelights on the Remarkable Dizzy Dean (The game's greatest pitching motion; bench duty), Feb. 12-15, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - How a Champion Used to Look (Jess Sweetser with father, George), Feb. 18, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - Ever Hear of a Pitcher Named Ed Walsh?, Feb. 19, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Last Meeting of Two Star Rivals (Chick Evans, Francis Ouimet), Feb. 20, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - A Record that Stood for 16 Years (Ted Meredith), Feb. 21, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When Great Britain Ruled the Bunkers (Harry Vardon, James Braid, Sandy Herd, J. H. Taylor), Feb. 22, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Start of a Famous Hike (Bunion Derby), Feb. 25, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - The Siege Gun Passer (Brick Muller), Feb. 26, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
      - When the Wild Cat Ruled (Ad Wolgast with wife), Feb. 28, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 48-60)
  - "Setting the Pace" (Box 7, Folder 61-70)
  - "Setting the Pace" (Box 8, Folder 1-10)
  - "Grantland Rice" (column) (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - Non-newspaper publications, Non-newspaper publications: programs with poems by GR (1936-52) (5 items); other publications with poems by GR (6 items); sheet music, poems by GR set to music (1930-1945) (6 items) ("Come on, You Commodores," "Donald the Dub," "And Then He Took up Golf," "Vanderbilt Forever, "For the Glory of T.C.U.," "I Lift My Glass," "Above the Darkness"); poetry booklets, Base-Ball Ballads (1910), Steel and Flame (1942); prose by GR appearing in non-newspaper publications ("The Golf Course that Surprised Me," "The Grand Ole Dope," "How Champions Are Made," "Devices for the Duffer," "Dressing to Beat Par," printed quotation with picture, "What's Wrong with Football," "Golf's Greatest Putt," "Bing Plucks a Pigeon," "Grantland Rice Says," "The All Time All Stars of Baseball"); The Duffer's Handbook of Golf, galley proofs; Spalding's Golf Guide (edited by GR), 1917, 1919, 1920, 1921, 1922, 1924, 1928, 1929; Cities Service Football Guide, 1933, 1936, 1937, 1938, 1939, 1940, 1941, 1947, 1950." (Box 8)
- Newspaper Clippings
  - About Grantland Rice, before 1914 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - About Grantland Rice (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - About Grantland Rice, 1954 January - June (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Book Reviews (Box 9, Folder 21-23)
  - Play Reviews (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Film Reviews (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Publicity for Columns (Box 9, Folder 26-27)
  - Publicity for other writings, including All-America teams (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Publicity for Books (Box 9, Folder 29-30)
  - Publicity for Films and Radio Program (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Chesterfield and Rheingold advertisements (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Undated Pictures (Box 9, Folder 33-34)
  - Undated Columns (Box 9, Folder 35-38)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 39-40)
  - Grantland Rice's family (excluding Florence Rice) (Box 9, Folder 41-42)
  - Grantland Rice's Death (Box 9, Folder 43-46)
  - Grantland Rice's Funeral (Box 9, Folder 47-48)
  - Editorial Tributes (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Other Tributes (Box 9, Folder 50-53)
  - Typed transcripts of newspaper articles with comments (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Letters to the editor, articles on estate (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous references and tributes (Box 10, Folder 2-5)
  - Grantland Rice dinner at Toots Shor's (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Look Magazine Football Writers award (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Plaques etc. (including V.U. bust) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Sportsmanship Brotherhood Award (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
  - Sunshine Park Grantland Rice Handicap (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
  - Birthplace plaque (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Scholarships, Columbia and Vanderbilt (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
  - Miscellaneous memorials (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Programs, etc. - memorial dinners and luncheons (Box 10, Folder 17-19)
  - Biographical articles and sketches (Box 10, Folder 20-26)
    Biographical articles and sketches: Edwin Alger sketch (12 typed pages), Fred Russell sketch (3-page typed carbon), J.G. Wharton sketch (3-page typed carbon), American Biography sketch (o typed pages with corrections in pencil); unsigned sketch entitled "Foreword" (17 typed pages); Encyclopedia of American Biography galley proof (see ms. sketch aboveTj" 2 Who 's Who in America entries, clipped and mounted for revision; clipping from Current Biography with sketch and photo of GR; address by Ralph Hayes at GR Dinner, 1951; 2 brief unsigned comments on GS, typed, 1 with jDencil corrections.
  - Poems to and about Grantland Rice, manuscripts and clippings (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Articles (non-newspaper) about Grantland Rice (Box 10, Folder 28-31)
    Articles (non-newspaper) about GR, 1942-1965, include articles by Henry McLemore, Leo Dolan, Harold A. Williams, James N. Young, Robert A. McGaw, Louise Davis, Red Smith, Charles Cason, John N. Wheeler, and V.U. Alumni 8c Development Office.
  - Radio scripts about Grantland Rice, Bing Crosby: 1954; J Phil Rizzuto: 10-31-62, 8-21-65, 1-12-66, 5-21-66 (Box 10, Folder 32-33)
  - About Florence Rice (Box 10, Folder 34-50)
    - Dartmouth Winter Carnival (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - June Moon (Box 10, Folder 35-36)
    - Marriage to Sidney Smith (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - She Loves Me Not (Box 10, Folder 39-40)
    - Films (Box 10, Folder 41-43)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 44-45)
    - Marriage to Robert Wilcox (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Films and Play (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Marriage to Frederick Butler (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Films (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 50)
- Photographs
  - Index to Identified Photographs
    - Abbott, Bill (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Alberti, Jules (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Army football team (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Artists and Writers Tournament (Box 11, Folder 4, 5, 7, 24)
    - Baker, Henderson (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Banner, Gail (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Barbee, J--- (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Barber, Red (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Barnhill, Ray (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Barry, Jimmy (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Barton, Bruce (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Bayless, A.B. (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Beach, Rex (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Benson, W.A. (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Bezdek, Hugo (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Bradley, Hugh (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - British Empire Games (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Brook, Indiana (Box 12, Folder 13, 28)
    - Brophy, Jim (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Bronson, John (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Brown, Admiral Babe (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Butler, Fred (Box 11, Folder 37, Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Byrne, Austin (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Camerer, David (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Camerer, David - house (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Carlson, Oscar E. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Carr, W.M. (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Carroll, Madelaine (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Carsey, Overton (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Carter, Phil (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Chase, Dan (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Cheek, Robert (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Churchill, Winston (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Citation (horse) (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Clark, Bobby (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Clement, Frank (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Coaltown (horse) (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Cobb, Ty (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Coe, Charles Francis (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Cohane, Tim (Box 12, Folder 7, 9, 25)
    - Colby, Anita (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Condon, Frank (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Connerly, Chuck (Box 12, Folder 9)